Joshua Dolgin

647-618-4031

Jdolgin@uwaterloo.ca

in/josh-dolgin

Profile

Smart, highly motivated mechatronics engineering student with experience in mechanical, electrical, and software engineering through five co-op terms. I have over six years of experience with CAD software, designing security cameras & accessories, robotic end effectors, and automotive sensor housings. Outside of Academics, I am an avid rock climber and snowboarder.

Skills

Hardware: SOLIDWORKS, Fusion 360, OnShape, NX, Creo, Altium, EAGLE, FEA, Simulation, Generative Design

Software: C++, C, Python, Verilog, System Verilog, Assembly, VBA, SQL, GIT, CSS, MATLAB

Work History

Verkada, San Mateo, Ca

Sept 2023 - Present

Product Design Mechanical Engineer (Cameras)

- Managed the creation of RFQ and PRD documents for a cutting-edge security camera project, ensuring clear communication of project specifications to all stakeholders.
- Led the mechanical design efforts for the EVT, and DVT phase of the new security camera, projected to increase yearly profits by \$500,000+.
- Collaborated closely with overseas vendors to implement DFMA principles, optimizing the production process for the security camera designs and reducing BOM cost by 30%.
- Conducted comprehensive IP and IK testing on existing and new security cameras, validating their performance and reliability in various environmental conditions, and contributing to product quality improvements.

Kindred Al, Toronto, On

January 2023 - April 2023

Robotics Hardware Engineer - On Grid Robotic Pick

- Researched and fabricated custom FDA-compliant suction cups with varying durometers using urethane casting.
 Increased pickable grocery items by 10% and improved maximum robot acceleration by up to 15% for certain items.
- Implemented DFMA methodologies to design high-volume, precision parts for next-generation robotic pick end effectors.
- Built an object that has configurable mass and porosity to imitate any pickable grocery item, which is used to identify
 maximum robot acceleration for individual SKUs.
- Performed FEA on multiple parts to reduce weight by up to 25%, and identify areas of high stress.

OMERS Ventures, Toronto, On

May 2022 - August 2022

Software Developer

- Developed a signal processing pipeline to notify teams of potential deals, by using Prefect to orchestrate Python code that leveraged various web scraping tools, Web APIs, and SQL databases.
- Created a 5 ft x 5 ft custom, open-source <u>Word Clock</u> for the reception area, with completely original 3D printed and CNC machined pieces, and embedded C software. The clock is capable of telling time in 3 distinct time zones, and includes various other animations and functions.

Untether AI, Toronto, On

September 2021 - December 2021

Al Accelerator Hardware Engineer

- Wrote Python code to instantiate Verilog test modules with customizable I/O hubs and communication lanes, automating the writing of multiple test bench modules, the modules were capable of verifying up to 98% of the hardware.
- Researched and implemented a variety of passive/active cooling techniques and configurations on TsunAlmi, a GPU sized device that contains 4 of Untether Al's accelerator chips.

NMC Dynaplas, Scarborough, On

January 2021 - April 2021

Manufacturing Engineer

- Designed and fabricated multiple test fixtures (3D printing, Machining) to hold parts for CMM measuring, reducing the average time to measure parts by 500%.
- Analyzed Engineering drawings to create CMM measuring routines and wrote excel VBA software to populate documents with the data after measuring, almost completely removing human measurement from the QA process.

Education

University of Waterloo, BASc, Mechatronics, GPA: 3.99/4.0